A Guide to the David Rockefeller papers, Office Files, Office of David Rockefeller FA1830
Rockefeller Archive Center
David Rockefeller papers, Office Files, Office of David Rockefeller
1934-1997
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, David (1915-2017)
FA1830
5.13 Cubic Feet 13 letter document boxes and 1 half-letter document box.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research in accordance with the terms of donation from the David Rockefeller estate. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Consists of condolences, correspondence, reports, international affairs, investments, and estate files.
Arrangement
Original order, as received.
- Peggy Rockefeller Condolence files - A-C, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
- Peggy Rockefeller Condolence files - C-F, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
- Peggy Rockefeller Condolence files - G-J, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
- Peggy Rockefeller Condolence files - K-M, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
- Peggy Rockefeller Condolence files - M-R, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
- Peggy Rockefeller Condolence files - R-V, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
- Peggy Rockefeller Condolence files - W-Z, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
- Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Correspondence regarding her letters, 1957-1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Abby Mauze Correspondence, 1951-1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Rockefeller, JDR 3rd - Correspondence, 1947-1978 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Rockefeller, JDR 3rd - Memorial Service Booklet, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop - Correspondence, 1947-1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop Death of - General, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop Death of - Condolence letters - A - Z, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop - Estate of, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Rockefeller, JDR Jr. - Correspondence, 1959-1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Rockefeller, JDR Jr. - Death of, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Rockefeller, Martha Baird - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Rockefeller, Martha Baird - Death of, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Nelson Rockefeller - Correspondence, 1942-1956 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Nelson Rockefeller - Correspondence, 1957-1989 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Nelson Rockefeller - Political, 1959-1963 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Nelson Rockefeller - Political, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Rockefeller Brothers Meetings - Correspondence, 1951-1978 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Angola, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Africa, 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Cameroon, 1982-1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Cuba Trip - Human Rights, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Cyprus, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Guinea File, 1982-1992 (Box 10, Folder 8-9, Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  General
  4 folders
- Iran - Administration-General, 1979-1981 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Iran - Clippings, Articles, 1979-1981 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Iran - David Rockefeller's "Foreign Affairs" article, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Iran - Professor George Lenczowski Report, 1979-1981 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Iran - Shah of, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  Scope and Contents
  1990 correspondence between H.M. Farah Pahlavi and David Rockefeller concerning assets held at Chase
- Ivory Coast, 1983-1987 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Morocco, 1982-1985 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Mozambique, 1984-1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Senegal, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Zimbabwe, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- David Rockefeller - Annual Review of David Rockefeller's Associations and Responsibilities, 1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- David Rockefeller - Finance, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- David Rockefeller - Investments, 1984-1990 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- David Rockefeller Trusts - David Rockefeller Charitable Trusts - Trustees Meeting, 1990 October 5 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted - David Rockefeller Estate - Open in 2042
- David Rockefeller Trusts - Charitable Lead Trusts - Remainder to Children, 1983-1985 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- David Rockefeller Trusts - DR - Remainder to Harvard College, 1982 November 1 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- David Rockefeller Trusts - Descendants of David Rockefeller, 1969-1992 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- David Rockefeller Trusts - David Rockefeller & Descendants Partnership, 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
- David Rockefeller - 1934 Trust, 1987-1992 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Restricted - DR 1934 Trust - Open in 2027
- Embarcadero Investment Corporation (EIC) - Edgewater, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Embarcadero Investment Corporation (EIC) - General, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Embarcadero Investment Corporation (EIC) - Rock & Co, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- ECIP, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- ECL - General, 1992-1997 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- ECL - Hyatt Regency - San Francisco, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Embarcadero Center West (ECW) - Financials, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Embarcadero Center West (ECW) - Investor Associates, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Embarcadero Center West (ECW) - Park Hyatt, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Embarcadero Investment Corporation (EIC) - Long Beach Pike, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Embarcadero Investment Corporation (EIC) - New Project Prospect, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 14-15)
- Embarcadero Center - Overview, 1992 January 21 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Rockefeller & Associates Realty Reorganization, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  Restricted - David Rockefeller Estate - Open in 2027
- Rockefeller & Associates Realty (RAR) - Edgewater, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Rockefeller & Co. - David Rockefeller Investments, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Rockefeller Trust Company, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Sheridan Realty Corporation, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Venrock, 1987-1989 (Box 12, Folder 19)